The Gujarat Industry Development Association
and SMV Chamber of India Stand Committed
To Be Your Partners in the Journey Today
Tomorrow and Always
Thank you for being here with us while we let you make
The Most of This Evening to Learn, Connect and
Build a Stronger More Resilient MSM
Ecosystem Together I Look Forward To
Enriching Sessions Ahead and Two to Witnessing the
The Collective Energy of the Summit Translates Into
The
Actions. Friends, I would like to thank you
ICICL Low General Insurance Company Limited.
please give them a big ground of
Clause. And I would like to invite Mr.
Shivam Sharma, Deputy Vice President, SME
Agency ICICIIIIIIIIII
Lumbard General Insurance Company Limited
For the welcome address. Oh Sir, good evening
Everybody good evening
There was a lot of noise in Surat
Good evening everyone, good evening
It's an absolute pleasure to welcome you all
On this exciting MSME knowledge session I
May welcome to all of you and extend a very
Special Welcome to Our Partners SMEs
Chamber of India and Gujarat Industry
Development Association Guest and All All The
Entrepreneurs and the Business Leaders Who Are
Joining Today We Are Truly Delighted To Be
Here we gather, here we stand
Important Crossroads in the Journey Which
is shaping MSMEs we know that MSMEs is
The Backbone of the Economy Driving Innovations
Generating Employment and Contributing
the overall growth of the nation however with the
The Rapidly Changing Business Landscape It Is
Crucial to Ensure That Businesses Are
Empower with the right tools, knowledge and
Strategies. Even if the face of uncertainty
And the risk our goal is clear to share
Innovative Solutions and Effective Risk
Management Strategies Will Equip MSMEs
To Build Reliance and Continue to Grow
Sustainably.
In the ever-evolving business environment
Today We Have the Privilege of Hearing the
Industry leaders, the experts who will
Share their valuable inputs and insights
About the Practical Knowledge About Whatever
The SMEs are doing it as a part
of this session we will also be hosting a
Panel discussion which will delve deeper into the
Subject Line Your Presence Here Today Is
A Testament and the Collective Desire to
Learn Innovative and Adapt the Fact That So
Many have chosen to take time out of their
Busy schedule to be a part of this session
Demonstrates the Commitment You All Have
Towards Growing Business and
Contributing to the Nation's Economic
Development One Important Thing Before We
Proceed since this is an exclusive close.
Door Event We Kindly Request You To
Reframe from Taking Any Photographs and
Videos during the session additionally we ask
You do not share any promotions and events
Related content on social media, WhatsApp
And any other social medias. This will ensure
The Focused and Private Space of All the
Participants. Once again I welcome each other
Everyone of you. I'm confident that this
The session will provide you with the valuable tools
And the Insight That Will Ever Let You Face It
Challenges Head On and to Help Your
Businesses Build a Resilient and
Prosperous Futures. Let's make today a
Learning & Networking & Growth Session.
Thank you all. Enjoy the session.
Thank you Shivam ji. a now i would like to
Invite Mr. Ankit Goyal Associate Vice
President ICI Lomard General
Insurance for his presentation over sir
Please please give a big ground of clauses
To Him Good Evening to Everyone
Come on, that's great. We heard it somewhere now
If you want to sleep peacefully, wake up. So this
Insurance Brings You the Mental Peace of Mind
Mind because you have invested your hard
Earn Money in Your Businesses and You Are the
The backbone reason being you're running the country
You are providing services you are
Providing Your Material You Are The
Manufacturers You Are The Trail Brazers
of this India so over to this
Presentation Salam MSME Master Class So
what is
MSME Can We Have Answer From Anyone Yes
Micro
ok so what do you mean by micro and
Small Management
Services? slab
Ok. So definitely in India we have a
market space and industrial space which
Has been divided into various segments.
Somewhere is SME, somewhere is MSME,
Somewhere Is Big Market and Ah Big
Industrial Markets and Conglomerates.
Ok? To the next page please.
Ok.
did not stop
Over to the need of insurance. Why Do We
Need insurance? So insurance is not only
Provides you the financial security it
also provides you the opportunity to
Take More Risk Into Your Business. How It Is
Happening? So suppose you have an investment
of 100 crore, 50 crore and 150 crore in your
Business. If anything miss happens to your
Business like if there is any natural
Calamity Event If There Is Any Fire To
Your Premises Where the Money Will Come From
To compensate your losses into your business so
This insurance will make
Sure That You Will Get Timely Money for the
Losses We Have Faced During This
Incidents. Risk exposures. so what
Is risk exposures to be in a very
Precise Manor is yours, whatever asset you have.
Whatever the business risk, which has been
Exposed to these losses is called risk
Exposures. So it is very much evident
From the photo like the entire factory is
Being Gated Into the Fire. so what
Happens When There's a Fire? you have a
Loss of your assets. We have a loss of faith
stocks, we have a loss of plant and
Machinery. And because the entire machinery is
Down and Gated in the Fire. there will be no
Production. And because there is no material
Being Produced You Cannot Sell
Anything. If you can't sell anything, you
Can't earn anything. There Will Be a Loss
to your asset as well as loss to your
Profits. So coming to this point. Ah Wei
Have four parameters like risk
Identification.
Whatever business you are in, there will be some
Inherent Risk to Your Business. if you are
Into the Business of Chemicals You Can Get
Dealing in solvents which may be
Hazardous and flammable in nature and it is
Very much necessary to identify the inherent
Risk into your business. Coming to the
Next Point: Measuring the Risk Exposures
To the business. How much and up to what
extent you are being exposed to your
Business. Suppose if your plant is a bean
divided into various parts and they are
Very much separated from each other. if there
There's a Fire in One Block Possibly You Can
Prevent Your Other
Block. Then third is risk mitigation. What
Is it risk mitigation? how you are acting
According to your business to eliminate these
Risk. The risk of fire, the risk of
Business, the Risk of Loss of Profit and
Everything. The Risk Due to Begal. then there
Comes risk protection. You can have your
Risk Protection by Transfer of Risk
Mechanism. How do you transfer risk?
Mechanism by Purchasing an Insurance
Policy. anything happens on your premises
Is. You purchased an insurance policy
Is. That policy in that event will make sure
that whatever loss you have suffered will be compensated
Let's do. This is how you are transferring
Your risk.
So What Can Happen to Our Business Like
Fire Workman Compensation
You have certain people and employees and
Laborers who will be working with in your
Premises on contract basis
Someone dies on the premises
There's a Family and The Contractors May Su
If you are against them, you will have to pay a
Compensation so there is a WC policy
Which make the payments against this
Compensation then there is less cyber risk.
Risk has been increasing daily at a very
steep rate year in in India because we are
Very much exposed to such risk because we
Are not very much aware about the cyber risk
In cyberspace, so we have cyber
Insurance as well then there come third
Party
Liability anyone who does not belong to
Your premises who does not belong to your
Business comes to your premises and because
Anything is happening to others
People That Will Be Triggering the Third Party
Liability. If you say in Hindi, your
constitutional
obligation. The third is Burglary of Theft.
We have seen certain number of premises in
People enter the premises at night.
They enter. They do damage your
Buildings. They Do Damage Your Shutters. Give
Take away your materials. so that can also
Get covers within the same policy. Cash End
Transit cash in safe. Probably since we
Are in the business? Definitely there will be some.
Money Transactions You Will Be Collecting Your
Money During the Day Hours You Will Be
Sending your employees to the banks for the
Deposit if someone comes in the way if someone robs
Someone becomes Lasni, someone becomes their
Assault Happens That Can Be Covered Under
The Cash in Transit and Cash in Saved | Now
What is Cash and Safe in your office?
There must be a safe kept somewhere where you
People keep their cash safe if any
Buglery happens to that safe safe along with the
Damage to the Building That Can Get Covered In
The Cash and Safe. Similarly, we have marines.
Cargo, Machinery Breakdown, Fidelity,
Electronic Equipment Insurance and
Directors and Officers
Liability. So this is a 360
Degree V can to a diagram and the
Requirement of the Insurance. how does it
You know reflects your MSME sector. So
If I come to hospitality, what do they need?
In Hosp Hospitality We Have Hotels There
Can there be instances of fire in hotels there?
Can be instances of you know earthquake
Where the entire building gets damaged
There Can Be Riots That Can Get Covered
Under fire policy then there is a cyber
Space CGL Commercial General
Liability simultaneously for IT offices
You have you are running your you know software
Development Company
Ok. So you have to hold a lot of amounts of
Laptops, Digital Servers and You Know
Digital Tapes and Drives to Save Your
Data that generates a huge amount of heat
Because of any electrical short circuit
That Can Catch Fire. So You Can Protect
Your entire premises along with your
Belongings and to your assets with in the
Same fire policy. Same is textile.
Now we work with textiles inside textiles.
Are doing. It will contain cotton and cloth.
There will be many different things. they all are very much
Flammable. Then what is Marine? Marines
Insurance? You purchase something. Any
From manufacturers' premises
Material is arriving at your premises. If
During that journey anything happens to that
cargo which belongs to you for which you
Have paid the money. that will be compensated for
that
Loss. Then we have manufacturing sector.
Manufacturing sector compares
Anything Like If You Are Inu
Manufacturing of Chemicals If You Are Inu
Manufacturing of
Plastics Health Care Industry
Electrical Manufacturing Premises
Like we have various names you will see in the
Upcoming Slides
Ajantacon as examples of risk
Exposures in the Insurance.
Recently we have seen a fire in this
Premises. How Many of Us Are Aware
About this? Why
Happened? So why this has
What happened? anyone from
You? So I want to make this session a little
Interactive. So let us be vigilant and awake.
Stay. So what do you guys think? What
There must have been a reason for the fire here? Short
Circuit. Short circuit. Very Small Reese's Joe
We always neglect. We meditate
I don't give. The wiring is old.
Wiring from inside electrical panels
It is hanging. Proper time for things
No maintenance, timely corrective
Do not take action. so big because of it
There seems to be a fire. We don't even think about it
If a fire breaks out, the building will also be damaged.
will be. Our goods lying there are damaged.
will be. Finnish stocks. So Everything Is
At Risk. Unless we take corrective action.
If there is no fire insurance policy here
What would have happened if it had happened? Entire Burden of Your
Business will fall upon your head. and at that time
How distressing it would be when we have
There will be no insurance. Goods worth crores are moving
Will go. 10 years of hard work, 15 years of hard work
Which you people have started your business and empire
Has been erected. So that is why the
Insurance Very Merchant End
Necessary. That's why I said it not only
gives you the mental peace, it gives you the
Confidence to Stand
Again. So s per the industry
Statistics We Have Seen Like 20,000
Deaths per year caused just because of fire.
56% of disasters are because of the electrical
Faults. And this is not only through the
India. I must quote a report from
Allianz Global Which Is An International
Entity working through the world. even in
There report they have mentioned that majority
70% of fires are arising out
Off Electrical Fs. And that's the report
Was published in the year of
2022. donation
80% of fires are caused by electrical
Installation with in India. simultaneously
You must have also seen that if I look at the last 50
If I talk about years, whatever natural
Calamities are earthquakes,
Tornados,
Typhoons and cyclones don't occur so often before.
Were. Heavy Rains,
Storms, water accumulation.
Recently we saw inside Baroda
All the losses came simultaneously, we have seen
Business Joy Taut the Rates of Recurrence of
The events have increased. in 3 years no
Nor does any natural disaster occur. Now
This is very evident because we
I have been watching this for so many years. last 50
Every three natural disasters occur within a year.
It is almost certain to come this year. so it is
Our duty to take fire insurance and the
MSME. We have a separate MSME
Product Developed Specifically for You
Ficus religiosa. In which all these types of things are covered
Is. Everything is covered. It's a bundled
Package
Product. So here we will see a small you
No Insights About the Insurance Industry
How the Insurance Industry Works and
What it is. So if you know the new India
This is actually a PSU public sector
Undertaking that a Government Company having
The Largest Business Base in India. We Are
A private sector leader and we are just a
Little bit after this new India.
ICICI Lombard has grown and you know
Reached to this place based upon there
Clients Based Upon the Trust We Have With
In Our Clients. Our Claim Settlement
Our Value Added Services
Our risk mitigation services to clients
To educate. These are the important points
What keeps our clients connected with us
Is. What are the client's expectations?
Is? Should I just take a policy? Then I next
I will show you my face only when I have to
Want to take premium? No. It Requires
Continuous engagement with the client. It
Requires continuous teachings to the
Clients. What are you doing right? What's wrong
Are you doing it? Is there an improvement in risk?
Is required? Where do we find improvements?
Do you want to bring it? That Entire Thing Will Be Taught By
The ICSC Lobard Age Well. so we have a
Separate Team in Our Company Which Look After
All This
Requirements. So If You See This Is Ours
Ranking in Fire We're Just Behind the
New India we are at the rank second in
Engineering. We're Having Hardly Any
Difference. In This Year I Must Say We Will Be
You know crossing new India as well in
Engineering Business As Well As In Fire.
Marine and Liability We are already leading the
Sector.
So this is a small overview about our
Finances and the company performance we have
Done this is still December 25th we have already
Done
₹66
20623 crore of business then this is profit
1999 crore after tax, many insurances
The total annual premium of the company is also the same
Not there. so you can understand the size of
Our company. You Can Understand the Claim
Paying capability of our company. How
How Capable We Are and How Strong We Are. donation
We have 28.1 million policies
Issued. Our presence is more than 625
Located within the districts. solvency
Ratio where PSUs are government companies
Is 1.5. R Solvency Ratio Is Just Double
To them. It shows that our financial
The backing is very strong. We are someone
Don't be afraid of big claims
Is. So this is a global award which we
Have born in the year of 23 and 24 which
Shows that our commitment, our presence
Towards this sector towards our you know
Industry and Towards Our You Know
These are certain big names which have been
Associated V ICICI LBAT Hero RBI HCL So
Pidelite RL Mittal Adani JSW & First
Source Hyundai BJUS Infosys ITC I Must
Say there are certain names whose size
So huge are the premiums and policies
You Can Never Imagine If I Know You Discuss
about adani and JSW they have 600 crores of
Asset located at a single location and Adani
Has a total asset insured with
As000
Cr Ircon Exide Serum Institut Serum
Institute If You Remember This Is The Same
Company which has developed the vaccines
for corona so when there was a fire
incident it was also
Insured Tata Steel Furniture HTAC Tata
Project K Gemini Fizzer ncle Reliance
Folkham
Flipkart so why we are
Best Focus
Here this is the largest capacity of any
Insurance company in the private sector.
We are the ones who can handle one of the
Largest and biggest risk in India.
That shows that our fire
PML Basis of 1400 Crore on Capability.
Then we are technologically very much advanced
As compared to our competitors. We Do
Provides digital platforms, real time
Tracking of the policy, real time tracking
of the
Claims, Risk Mitigation Measures, Fire
Walls, Fire Extinguishers, IoT
Devices, CRA, CPM, Waste Service
which is all provided by ICICI
Lobard. Generally you people go in contract
With certain fire safety devices, Ah Fire
Safety Companies Who Do Provide Such
Services. But we have an internal
Department to Cater All These Dips
Requirements of Years. And We Do
Provide service at a very competitive
Rates are compared to the
market. So yes the name MSME Suraksha Kavach
Policy which is specifically been designed for
The MSME sector. You know we have done this
Product Looking After Your
Requirements. Looking After Your
Needs. Our claims are our strength. 90%
95% of the claims get settled in 90 days
Days for the Marine for Property We Do Settle
For up to 5 lakh claims, we will claim for the next 10
Settles within days. And Ah We Are
Also into the development of new things.
We are coming up with the new facilities.
Digital Facilities Where You Can Know What You Lose
Your claims are settled via the app. You can track your
Where are the claim settlement procedures?
The status of your claims with in that app
itself than we have health facilities we
Have a Cash Biggest One of the Biggest Cashless
Network Due Liability
Average Count of the Claims We Have Managed
2000 plus per year
[music]
Oh wait a minute I just forgot to mention one
of that point so if you see executive
Tie ups. So it's not only with in this
Space We Have Executive Tie Ups For
You know big investigators, then lose.
Adjusters, Lawyers, Cyber ​​Consultants
Where in they come and provide the technical
Assistance in the claim settlement as well as
The Client's Understanding. The client has many
Doubts remain. I have to ask many things
Are. So they provide there you know they come with
Their Expertise for Your
Solutions. So these are some of the paper cuttings
Which has been mentioned in the market.
If you see and read ICICI Lombard 10 days
She claims to settle it in. which we have
Already seen and you can cross verify
From the Market as well. MSME Claims
Up to Rs 5 lakh to be settled with in 10 days
ICICI Low LBA to settle claims up to Rs 5 lakh
10 Days with up to 5 lakh with in the 10
Days so it is our commitment and these are not
The only words we know are you
are following it very religiously because our
Market reputation depends upon it. We
Similar to this in the market in the last 20 years
Did not become a leader. Claim settlement is ours
Strength. The clients who are associated with us
Once they join, they don't leave.
Is. And this is the data which has been
Published on the IRDA website which is
Available in the open forum. You Can See the Lines
In the Orange Then Blue. Blue Represents The
Other companies which are settling the claims
Warehouse Orange Represents ICICI LBAT V
R at the 73% of the claim settlement ratio
Other companies are 64% where as 32% is the
PSUS Where It Is Property Health Marine
We are leading
Everywhere This Is Our Risk Management
journey and it is very much needed for an
organization which is into the business of
Insuring Risk They Need to Have a Core
Understanding and Competency in the Risk
Mitigation a well. If my competency
If not in risk mitigation then how will I
Be Understanding Your Risk? How I Will
B. Insuring Your Risk. so we have a good
I must say a network of in-house
Engineers Who Go to the Clients
premises where you no longer inspect them
Premises They Prepare Reports for the
Clients when they mention that your risk
and in your premises or factory
What is the scope for improvements?
Where do you need to improve your risk?
What are the factors where you should pay attention?
Have to give. So that you can help any person who comes
Accidents can be avoided in advance
yes.
So Avoiding Claims Helps You Bring In
Down the premium. Sleep Loss Prevention and
Control, Property Risk Assessments,
Health checkups, digital initiatives. V
Have IL Take Care App. So That App Helps
You for the claim settlement, filing of the
Click to check the status of the claim. It's
Not Only for the Property Lines of Business
As Well As It Works for the Health Business.
Where in you have GMC policies, group
Mediclaim Policies, Group Personal
Accident Policies, GPA
Policies. When we were in 2015, we
Started Loss Prevention and Control
Department 2018 We Came Up With The Asset
Valuation and Marine Loss Engineering
Department that was you know year when we
Added another feather to our cap. So, what is
Asset valuation? certain number of times
VCK Sir, I have taken a loan from the bank.
I have to get insurance of Rs 50 crore. When
If the claim is settled, the client says
Why did the claim get less? because they
Unaware of how much insurance they need
Was? What are their insurance requirements?
Was? So the valuation is an aspect
Where in if you go into the market for a
Valuer to Get Your You Know Assets Value
They charge you a very higher rate where as il
Provides you a very competitive rates
As compared to the market if you are a
Client to the ICIC
Loan Marine Loss Engineering Whatever you own
You do transactions naturally if you are
into the business if I am manufacturing
I will procure the raw material and if I
I have manufactured some, so my
I will sell finished products. And it will
Happen either by the way of using
Transportation by Road, Transportation
Bye Seas. If there are any losses there. Any
Inherent is something you can't see
Are. If losses are occurring again and again, then how can he
Can be reduced. how to improve it
Can be done. how to fix it
Can. What steps do you need to take
It is necessary that these claims of yours come. So that
We also have the cheese department in line.
Then Digital Initiatives We Prepare Ourselves
Virtual Risk Assessment Apps IL Tech
Care Apps in 2019: The Emerging Solution
Risk Cyber ​​Risk Solutions Given
Modernizing the Solutions IoT Solutions V
Will discuss it in the future
Slides a Health
Insurance So We Have a One of the Widest
Network of Health Providers and
Hospital Network in the Country We Have
10,000+ Network of Hospitals
Network Presents in 700 Plus
Locations Across the
India. How Technology Has Been Helpful
Comprehensive mobile apps are there. We
People just talked about IL Tech.
There is a care app. You have fallen ill. You your
You can file a claim. You are your status
You can see. Where is your claim stuck?
Where from? How much process did it take? When the process
will be? When will the claim be paid? all of that
You will see it in the IL Take Care app.
Then we are already 901 and 2015 certified
In-house investigation team for the fraud
V for Controls and Data Analytics
Are diving into the area of ​​AI Artificial
Intelligence We Will Be the First Company in
Market to Bring Artificial Intelligence
in the business of
Insurance then there is customer service us
People real time claims communication
Our in house own customer service 24/7
You can call representative centers or
You can call it call centers. Then Claim Help
Desk then claim strength cashless
Approvals We Provide Within 60 Minutes
And I think this is one of the fastest in
The Industry Across All the Insurance
Companies.
So the are different line of business fire
Engineering Marine Cargo Liability Group
Health one two three four five and then more
There will be WC and then there will be more GMC.
How many policies will the client handle?
It is the client's job to look after their business.
Not managing insurance
We are there to manage. So we have
Device a single product covering all the
Things. Same product under the same umbrella
Complete all your requirements below.
will be covered in a way. so you don't have
To you know get inu pain of renewal. Hey today
It did not become one. You only get one a year
Bar policy has to be removed. So We Do
Cover We Have This MSMA Safety Cover
Policy. where in we cover
Ah for Fire Engineering Miscellaneous
Section V Provides Coverage for Your Assets
Building Stocks Plant and Machinery
It will catch fire due to some natural calamity.
There was damage, someone created riots.
Massively damaged, any impact damage
Done That Can Get Covered Then Your Machinery
There was a breakdown and no damage was done to the machine.
If it gets damaged while travelling, then that too is covered in it.
There are electronic equipments
portable
Equipments and your cash
The dealing is cash in transit cash in
Save then flexibility to choose the custom
Covers, you said no, I need only this
Much of the cover I don't want it to be that big
Requirements Have Been Limited to Fire
MBD Money OK as much as you require
Take that much, it is not mandatory to purchase
Everything We Have a Bundle Product and You
Have the Option to Choose If You Don't Want That
Particular section you are not both to buy
It If You Can Select Whatever You Want
It's pick and choose model, same happens with the
Coverage as well as quick tat for the code
You request that you
Please fulfill these requirements of mine.
Regarding give me the code we have a tat
of 24 hours from single policy document
For the ease of administration and renewal
We just discussed that you need different
There is no need to take policies. you don't
Have to take the pain of renewing everything else
This policy is coming now, brother, this month
Policy No Everything Will Be Covered Under The
Single Policy and You Need to Take Care of the
Policy renewal only once in a month we have
Fire and F LOP Fire Look Because Sins
You people are into the business, you people.
Understand what insurance is
What will be the product but FLOP generally?
If I didn't know, I would put it simply
I will tell you about your factory.
If there is a fire in the factory of X person
If it is installed then production will not take place because
The factory will be closed. No production
If it happens then the goods will not be produced. If it will not be made then
It will not sell. If it doesn't sell, there will be no profit.
will be. So that profit is also covered
Under fire loss can be done
Profit. Your factory is damaged due to a fire.
It stopped. You are not able to produce.
Unable to sell my goods. Because of him
Whatever loss you incur, you can cover it under FLP.
Policy. Then MBD EI Boiler So The Falls
Under Engineering Segment Bugleri Money
Miscellaneous Fidelity So What Is Fidelity
If your employees commit any kind of embezzlement
We do infringement, we do internal
If you steal, that gets covered under the
Infidelity Section It's Basically Kind Of
Crime Done by Your Own Employees Buggery Koi
A third person comes and steals from you.
Damages the premises by taking goods
That gets covered under the money
We discussed what is always something
Such portable equipments are any digital
Equipments will be monitors and UPS
There will be mobiles, there will be some digital
Equipments will be which is been
specifically related to your business that
Get covered under the all risk policy then
Group Personal Accident Policy Public
Liability Policy WC Policy That
Gets Covered Under the Same
product than we have an option of
Selection of STFI and Terrorism
Earlier When the Products Was Released
by the Government of India under the
Supervision of GIC and IRDA there
Certain new products called Bharat Small
Enterprise Security and Bharat Micro Enterprise
Security. They were not providing an
Opportunity for the client for the selection
Of the parallels as well. But we have filed our
Own Product Where In You Can Save Your Money
By selecting the covers which you want.
Jewellers Block Policy. So basically this
Policy Specifically Designed for the People Dos
Who are in the business of jewellery? give if you
Deal in a small shop and a big showroom for the
Golds You and Diamonds So You Can Cover
Undertake this at your own risk
Policy. Then here comes the again important
Part Marine.
So how many of you are aware of the Marines
Insurance
Policies? so there is one coverage in this
This is called the waiver of under insurance.
What is this waver of under
Insurance? A if you will see this that when you
People take insurance. Ok? so like this
It is not necessary that you get 100% insurance.
Can take it. In these coming days
Suppose you took insurance today and when
Insurance for the entire year is running at that time
If you have something in between
Extra goods arrive or good held
Interest comes or if you purchase any
New Machineries. Ok? And if any
misshapens over there because of fire any
Kind of pales triggered over there and
Because of that, if you have some insurance
Inside, in the buffer of sum insured
It happens below. so that is also covered under
This policy that is the MSC security shield.
So you are in a total piece of this policy. This
Is this for MSME stand alone for
Inside the MSME segment
Has been made. So earlier which is older
We had the product inside which
Business sealed we used to say that was up
to 15% for MSMEs we have catered it up
To the 25%. So this is an huge point as an
Above Insurance Perspective Basis.
And this will give you relief and peace of
Mind also.
Thank you
Sir. So where we are at the Marine
Insurance? Fire, you understood it right.
Is. There is a factory, there is a location, there will be a fire.
What is Marine Insurance
Sir? Share your problems with us
do. We can use our expertise
It is for you. Yes, sure sir. Please
Provide the mic to the. machines we
If you are importing then marine is required for that.
Insurance is needed. Sure some raw materials
Are you importing or exporting
If you are staying then insurance is required for both.
Is it based upon FOB or CIF?
Value is used to determine whether you sell or purchase goods.
Yes, very good, this is according to him.
The insurance calculation is done.
Definitely. From KG Shipping
Logistics I Take The Marine Insurance For
My Exporters. Okay, great. one of the
Case I Took the Marine Insurance and the
Cargo Got Damaged In
Transit after reaching destination Kansani
Told me to take the claim from the
Insurance company ok but they denied saying
That we can't give you claim because of cargo
Reached After 90
Days we so in this case how can you help?
Ok. So this basic point I think most of
The people are not aware about it. so what
Is duration clause? Duration clause says that
How many days does it take for your material to reach where?
Needed? based upon the general practice of the
Shipping industry. If it is exceeding the
Extended limit. and then the material
If there is a delay, the claim is not received. If
It is because of the delay. But if the material
There is damage, you can have the concealed damage
Clauses with in your policies and those claims
You will settle down. specifically there is one
More advice also if you are taking a policy
Are. So it is always advice to go through the
coverages which is been covered with in the
Policies. Marine Insurance Policy Run Over
The Clause. The most important thing about marine insurance
This is Marine Insurance Throughout the World
The beans run. It is not that India's
Marine insurance inside will be different, for China
It will be different inside, it will be different inside the USA,
Will be different within the UK. No Marines
Insurance Clauses Are Same Across the World.
Point Number Two Marine Insurance Policies
Assignable Policy. You are your own factory
He will not name anyone. But yours
It is material and will pass through many hands.
Its ownership will change several times. So at the time when
Whoever is in ownership at the time of claim
The claim is settled by him. Depending Upon
The Ownership and Business Model of Money
Insurance. So I'll touch upon the basics
aspect of
Insurance. Hello hello it's better now.
So we have a single transit policy.
Marine Open Declaration Policy than we have
Marine Sales Turnover Policy
Now your A Marine Single Transit Policy Pay
Let's talk first. These are sometimes
The requirement comes. Suppose your
The business is local. You get a big order
Gone is what you have to transip out. So you
Once you take a Money in Single Transit Policy
Are. Which will cover only that transit.
Suppose my business today is hats and
To make heads. So he is as good as mine
Consumption takes place in the local market.
So being careless is not insurance.
takes. But I got a big order where
Deliver me 2000 or 3000 hats or heads
have to do
To UK market. So I thought about that
That now such a huge consignment has been delivered to me
If you want to do it and their value is high then I
Must take the insurance because it is regular
There is no transaction. It is a specific
I need to do a one-time transaction
For that I Marine Single Transit Policy
I will take it out. My goods are here from Surat
will come out of my factory and until he
Will not be delivered to the UK
If something happens to him on his way to the destination, that
Will be covered upon the single transit
Policy. Then There Comes a Marine Declaration
Policy. Now I am a manufacturer. My
The requirement is that I sell pan India goods
I sell and I sometimes requisition
If I have it, I sell it outside also. So you
What needs to be done? You will receive an initial
Do you assess your business that this
I will produce this much per year. near me
Orders worth ₹200 crore are already available.
So you can take a sum insured of ₹200 crore
You declare it to an insurance company
You told IL that you took ₹200 crore from me.
The sum is insured and whatever transaction I do
That maximum value will be 50 lakhs, one crore,
2 crores or whatever you want from your side 10 crores
I will do maximum transaction of Rs. So you
He said that the sum insured is Rs 200 crore. 100 million
I will have maximum value. Every month you
Send 100 trucks, send 500. near you
There is an online portal. You have your
You can enter the details. Today I have 50 lakhs.
If the transaction of Rs. 200 crores went
50 lakhs will be reduced because that much
It will be consumed. Your premium will remain the same.
It is consumed. So this is the only
Product Marine Insurance Where in You Pay the
Premium. The more you use, the more you pay
Will you do it? This is the beauty of this product.
You sent a transaction of Rs 10 crore today.
10 crore will be reduced from 200 crore.
Now you have left with Rs 190 crore. You
The second consignment was sold for Rs 20 crore. So
You have consumed Rs 30 crore from your
Business. That goods arrived safely. Suppose
by means of any reason that if your
The consignment truck that was going
It overturned due to an accident. Topple
Done. with another truck or trailer
or the railing he collided with or
There was theft in it. or on his way
Someone stopped me and robbed me. did you commit robbery or
Fire due to some accident in it
It's done. because of any reason on the way
Rights protests were going on. People have your
The contents of the vehicle were burnt. so there are
Numerous things. if something happens to him
It gets covered under the Marine Insurance
Policy. And as I said earlier
Had discussed. There are various clauses. When
We will discuss with you. Your Business
If we understand then we will advise you.
What are the benefits you get in Marine Insurance policies?
Clauses should be taken from. as I told
Concealed damage. It's a very beautiful
Clause. Conceal damage sez that mine
The material left from Surat and reached Pune. container
is locked inside. No damage to the container
There is no sign. But when I opened the container
I did it, took out the material, it was damaged. You
Will you tell me how is it possible? When the container has a
There is no damage. The seal of the container was placed in front of me.
It has opened. The container is open in front of me.
So how can material damage be removed from inside?
Is? So its forensic investigation
The insurance company will continue to pay the back end.
But under the Conceal Damages Clause, they
Claim Pay Tax
Will give. Then there is a sealed intake clause.
Time limit again in concealed damage clause
It is given for 30 days, 60 days, 90 days. So
If you don't necessarily want that container to arrive
So you will open it today itself. Project Cargo
Many times material comes inside
Is. Then he was kept inside the godown.
or kept in the yard
Is. When it is required,
It is opened at that time. And at the time when
If you test it, you will find that
There is something wrong with it. There is some damage in it.
So on the day your material was received, you
Didn't check it. you have checked it at a
Letter date. So even at that time, the claim that is made
It Gets Pay Under the Concealed Damage
Clause. So what do we understand about the
Liability?
If something happens to someone because of me, it will be me.
in court
Will drag. If you drag me to court, the court will drag me to court.
Some will order that you will need them so much
Compensation has to be given. So the compensation that
Hoga That Gets Covered Under This Liability
Policy. Now we have different products in
The Liability Policy. We have CGL,
DNO, Cyber, PI What is CGL?
Commercial General Liability.
You suppose I am manufacturing a
Cream. There is some mistake in my formulation.
And when she went to the cream market, she
When people put it on their faces
So people got rashes. someone's skin
What will he do if he gets some disease? suddenly
Go and file a suit against me in court.
Will do. Who will defend you now? Yours
defense costs, your PR costs, your
Goodwill, Brandwill, everything is at this
Steak. Then whatever the court awards from above
You have to compensate for that too, Defence
Cost also has to be paid. PR crisis
Management costs also have to be paid. that gate
Covers under the CGL. Your employee
Business partner or person to whom you provide material
Are you living there for some reason or business?
It goes because of the requirement. His
Due to the mistake, some damage would have occurred there.
Is. That gets also covered under the CGL
Policy. If anything happens like property
Damage and body injuries that get covered under
The CGL Policy. Product Completed
Operations Recall Options. Product Recall
Had to do it. Maggi was made bad. His
Some lead was found inside the spice. Complete
Recall it. Operation CGL like this too
Product Completed Operations and Recalls in
Options are provided under the scheme
Policies then there comes DNA directors
and officers
Liability being directors and officers in
Your Organization CEO
Director Managing Director U Tech
Certain Steps because of your steps
Your company is suffering some losses and
If some people in your company themselves listen to you
Because of your steps which are your
shareholders or those who are part of your business
Your partners are saying this
Loss to our business due to the mistake
It has happened and if you are worried about it
so all these things are covered under the
DMO Policies Anything Happening Because of Ha
Statements because of these statements because
of Your Actions Regarding the Business and
If It Is Creating Damage to Your Business
under goodwill and if any suit is made out of it
File Hota Hai That Care Covers Under DNA
policy than cyber we have a cyber cyber
Insurance Policy The Name Itself
Explains what the cyber is about. So
Cyber ​​Insurance Helps You If Someone Hacks You
Digitally withholds it. someone of yours
steals digital data from
Negotiations, data theft, data loss,
Forensic Expert Fees That All Get
Covered Under the Cyber
Insurance. Then Group Health.
So what are group health policies? Little
Some?
Idea. You are doing business. Your
Some will have 1000 employees, some will have 1000.
500, some 2000 depending upon the size
Of the business. You can give them a health boost from your side.
Provides insurance policy. to cover the
Entire Group. If the same person individually
If he goes to the market to buy a policy, he
It costs him dearly. where as when that group
If they take a policy after forming it, then they
It seems cheap. You get the price benefit, you
Get the Coverage Benefit, You Get the Prey
Existing disease benefit from day one,
This is called group health insurance
Policy.
So if you have new employees joining your
Company if you are an employee or a future
Coming employees will be inclined
Giving to join your organization
What is the health support available to us?
Have their own internal in-house health teams
We also conduct webinars from time to time 24/7.
Keep doing it for health being mental
Stress or mental harassment which is called stress
Yes, there is mental pressure, how to manage it
How can mental health be maintained well?
Is. How to maintain good physical health
Can it? So for clients like this
The webinars are also conducted by our company.
She arranges it. Then there comes how fast the
Claims are processed. This is the most
Impacting part of this policy. Ok?
Everyone provides benefits and add-ons. But
When you receive a claim, how quickly will you
Will you settle the claim, that brings the beauty
of this product. If someone is in the hospital
is admitted in, if the stress of his family
You want to see, then you will see. And when his
It happens on claim, with what joy he goes out
If he comes, he brings your employee with you.
Connects. That is the beauty of this
Product. Then There Comes How to Get the
Health Card Wellness Benefit. our own
IL Take Care is the app. So in earlier times
What used to happen in the olden days
You took a health policy and then it was in the company
Will go. Everyone's details will be known. a couple of months later
Health cards were printed. Then they come
Were. So We Overcome This Labs. How? You... Yourself
Will give a link to the applicants. You can use this app
Please download it. Your Employee ID or
Create your login. Inside this by date of
Birth, designation, everything will be auto-filled inside it.
you'll get. wherever you go you are there
You can select your hospital from that
Which hospital should I go to? Who do you
Sa Hospital is the nearest one. Which hospital
What facilities are there in it? how big
Is it a hospital? How far is it? Your claim
Filing will be done from there. Your claim
The processing will take place from there. To you
Approval is also available on your claim app
Will go. Your claim settlement will also be available to you on the app.
Will be seen. So, and your digital card is
Also on this. Now you have to go and get your card
You won't have to search. won't have to keep
Handle where is my policy? My
Where is the health card? It's Just a Simple
Mobile app. Everyone has a mobile phone in their pocket.
That digital card is yours within today's date.
In the pocket. You can get relief from this tension anytime, anywhere
It is free for me to take care of my health card.
or within such a Hap Hazard Time
You won't have to search. You your mobile
Open it, log in. in the hospital
Show me. Register details of TPA
Near. Get the admission in hospital and you are
Through the entire claim process.
So what are the productive strategies for?
The Risk
Mitigation? We have discussed about the
Different Lobs Like Property
Engineering, Marine, Health, Marine Cargo.
So these are the propositions. You now have fire
The extinguishers are placed in front of us. keep this
Are. But either we are aware how to use such
Devices? Isn't its date expired?
Is it done? Should I refill it?
Is? Is there a fire load on my premises?
Is too much? So I have to use the hydrant.
Will it have to? I'll have to use a hose reel.
I'll have to use sprinklers. You
People think what sprinklers will be?
Look at this little orange spot that appears
That is a sprinkler. If anyone here
Whichever way the fire occurs, it will get activated.
and all around
The water will spray. Because of that, if someone
Even if there is a fire, it will be extinguished. That Helps
To provide the protection at a very
Initial stage of the accident. If you do that
Let's invest in these things
Are along with your business. So your business
Lager is always safe for runs. You will never
Find a distress about such accidents.
Then I see this little cup on me.
Of plastic. It is called smoke detector.
No fire is visible but
Smoke is coming out from somewhere. it will
Detect the smoke and it will give you the
Siren. So all these facilities have been
Provided by the ICICI Lo LB Age Well.
In which we will show you fire balls, fire
Explains extinguishers. comprehensive
We give it after doing risk assessment. Yours
ICICI Lo LBA risk in factory
The engineer will go. He is the head of the entire factory.
I think photo
Ok.
Ok. So it is very important to risk
The engineer will do your complete assessment.
Will do the factory. He will spend two three
Hours in Your Factory. he will visit each
And every corner. He will visit everyone
Section of your factory where he will
Find what are short comings. Where
Pay improvement is needed. He is one
Will create a report. By creating that report, you
will tell you what improvements you need to make
Are. Then it is your choice whether you
Do you want to improve or not?
Want. But as an insurance company being
Your business partner. We will educate you
Regarding the improvements and risks.
Then IoT Fire Hydrant Electrical V
Have in-house patented products which can
Prevent such accidents we also
Provide that products than Marine Cargo
Inside we have telematics cargos
Inspections are Marine Loss Control
Management Unit, then for Cyber
We have cyber
There are security facilities, there are tools that
See what your products are
Weather they are very much a safe and not what you
Are you using a firewall that is correct or not?
Is. Then there comes the engineering. Brother
Comprehensive risk assessment that risks
The engineer assesses the fire.
Similar: We Have Engineers Who Do Risk
Assessment for your Engineering section.
What is the age of the machine? machine maintenance
Is it happening or not? Preventive
Do schedule maintenance, be proactive
Do maintenance, critical responses
Is it available or not? So, it depends
How much attention are you paying to your risk?
yes. And if you are not giving then we will tell you
That is, where is there scope. Where
There is scope for improvement. where you
Correction measures have to be taken. We are the checkup
We provide. Our vaccinations
There are drives. We had one in Corona
of the biggest vaccination drives by the
Insurance companies. Then OPD sessions are held.
People give. Along with that and many more
There are facilities which wherever you will know
Raise a query for the GMC policies you will
Get to know what facilities we have
We provide.
Question I'm open to answering your question
For your
Presentation.
Now we have a final session is going to be
Moderated by Mr. Kaushik Chandra Founder
and CO at connect and I will request the
Fellow panelists to please take a seat on
IS. I will request Mr. Ravindra
Tyagi Intermediate IIC General
Insurance Company Limited Mr. Ramesh Shah
CMD Excel Overseas Pvt Ltd
Mr. Rahul Gupta MD Bharat Lubicants
and Mr. Yash Sampath
Director Public Relations and Strategy
Alliance SME Insurance Promotion Council
please take your seat on the dias
And I
Will request Mr. Kaushik Chandra
To take forward the discussion. Over to you sir.
Please give a big round of clauses to the
Panelists. so without wasting any more
Time Everything Was Think We're Running Late
On that. And so let's start this discussion
Because everybody is waiting to hear from all
Of you. And I would request you know ah
Please introduce yourself for some time
Player so that you know the enter audience seating
out here can at least know about
Restriction. Good evening everyone. my name
I am Ravindra Tyagi and I am the managing
Director of Torque Insurance Brokers
Private Limited. this is basically
Insurance Broking House. We Are Pain
India Company having a pen India
Presence We Deal in All Sorts of
Insurance products. Thank you much. Good
Evening everyone. I am Rahul Gupta from
Bharat Lubricants. basically we are
Manufacturer and Explorer of All Kind
of Automotive and Industrial Lubricants
And we are working in pan India. We Are
Working Since 1984. It's a second generation
Business. Thank you so much. Good evening
Everyone. I am Yash Sampal. I am having 22
23 Years of Insurance Experience and
Right now we have set up an SME
Insurance Promotion Council Where I Am The
Director for Public Relations and
Strategic Partnerships
Hello good evening its Ramesh Shah from
Excel Overseas We are more than 35 years in
We are mainly in the gems and jewellery business.
100% Exporter We Have A Factory At
Ships at Sachin we have more than 200 workers
Working at the Present That's Ours
Introduction. Thank you so much sir. it is my
Privilege to Set No Amongst All This
Stallers in Respect for the Business
domains and I would like to continue with
This is asking you a question sir. how can
Innovative Insurance Solutions Amver Actually
The s MSMEs to build residences against
Unforced risk? It's really very good
Question. Abhi Friends Hindi English Kiss
Will I do it? I think that would be convent
For everyone Hindi English kya hota hai na
When someone needs insurance
So we get to know how much insurance they need.
Do you know what Ankit ji told you today?
what technological advancements
What things are happening because of this? All
People may be for the first time or many people
would have realized that technological
How much will SMEs benefit from advancement?
Benefit can be obtained and it is being obtained. Today
One, we remember that we first gave the industry 10
10-10 used to give 121 insurance policies
Were. Fire Insurance Policy Burglary Marine
Money WC right now a bundle of these
The product is the security cover of SMEs.
The product has all the coverage in it.
If you come under the policy then one of your
Saves you time to remember
It's not a problem that you know it's
My insurance comes on time and I
time pe aapki policy so basically you
Referring to the One Stop
shops and what is basically there that you
The base product, the base policy
You are getting more benefits. Perhaps
You must have seen that and the ICC Labrador which
It is known that the more
There should be more innovations within the product
Give more coverage to all those things
resides within the products. Add-on covers
You get benefits for you like
25% under insurance is unimaginable.
There was a way you could reduce your premium by 25%.
You are filling it, you understood its meaning, right?
Even after reducing your premium by 25%
You are getting 100% benefit. Correct
Sir. I mean with the permission of the audience
What will I do? I will keep on rotating
The Question with all the panelists. So That We
Can Hear From Everybody and What Are The
Views on it. Right? So I'm with Mr.
Ramesh Shah. I would like to ask you a
The Question That's How Do We Integrate
Innovative Risk Management Practices to
Protect Your Business in the James End
The jewelry section? In Gems and Jewellery
When we do mainly export business we are
Covered by the ECGC and the stock which
Is in the factory and in the office it is
Covered under the block policy. So It Helps
Quiet Lot and I Would Share My One
Experience during this Covid time one
Of my very old customer he failed but I could
Get all the claims by ECGC so in our
Business Mostly We Have Only This to Which
Helps for all to mitigate all the risks
Thank you sir with this I to mister
Arun CMD Sya Life Lines Pvt.
Limited and the question to you is what
Innovative Risk Management Strategies Do
You employ to ensure the residence of your
Pharmaceutical Manufacturing
Operations. The Question Was for You What In
Risk Management
Strategies That Would You Like to Employ
Ensure the residence of your pharmaceutical
Manufacturing
Qualities? I am sorry. He resides
Mr. Answer or or
If we talk generally about MSME, see
If we see the MSME sectors generally
If We Talk About the Losses
Losses MSME sectors you know it's a
Highly organized unorganized sector to
Because of the negativity you know we settle so
Many claims on yearly basis so what we
have seen due to the negligence of the people
Because all the employees are in the
Organizations are unskilled. So they are not
Trend Properly. so because of the
Unorganized Sector and the Negligence V
Generally settle so many claims. So it is the
Requirement of the Day That We Have to We
Have to know educate the people who are working
Organization. They need to know what they are
Risk Hazard which Mr. Ankit told that
The industry we work in today
What risks are involved in that industry?
Is. Either it is textile industry,
Pharmaceutical industry, oil industry
Anywhere Because of You Know Anyone Think
A small short circuit destroyed the entire Shiv
Shakti Market was destroyed. Now for this
There are many things in insurance. As
ICC Labrador has got a waste here
Facility Value Added Services in We You Know
Where these people through their equipment
How much inside your temperature wire
The temperature is rising. Can you understand?
Wire you can't feel that this water is
Heating you know you're not going to touch it.
But because of that Thermo Thermogon Thermo Joe
The gun comes because of that it will show that
The temperature inside the wire is increasing and
In the future it may you know short circuit. If
We go for such types of practices.
and such type of testing on regular basis
We Can Avoid Such Types of Accidents
which generally we see most of the claims are
happening due to short circuiting and
If We Go for Electrical Audit We Can
Remove all such things, you have no risk and this goes away.
Overlook Some Times You Know If We Don't Care
about it so much in that case so much with this
I go back to Mr. Ramesh Sah again with the
The Next Phase of the Question
What strategies have you implemented to
Insure the resilience of your business
Against the market
She's such with this new environment specially
This Trump's Terrific and All It Is Very
Difficult to Analyze Because Now for Us 26%
The jump in import duty is indeed a huge one.
That you know our business has almost like at
A Stance Still at This Moment But Time to
Time We Manage
Our Business Having a Preorder Before We
Take the order and after we buy purchase the raw
Material Like This We Cover Our Risk And We
Manage Our Profit But Try Being It
Very Difficult to Predict Our Industry
After this Trump for terrific and all so at the
The moment we also are under question mark
How we shall mitigate this risk so you are
In a Stage of Still Understanding How to
Get through that? Yes. because it's really a
Huge change ah that ah no one can absorb
Ah because our industry is with a very thin
Margin. We have a large turnover, Hughes
Turnover and margin is 35%. So, 26% is
To Hughes. So, but anyway, we and the
Diamonds When We Manufacture, Some
Diamonds Have a Attention, So That We Take a
Risk, I Had Manufactured One Stone
Almost worth 90 crores, one stone. And I
Took Insurance from IFFCO Tokio. h
Are my agent at this moment. May Be After
I will change to il also. that's a good
News. Let's see who is giving the best
Premium and all. Risk on the Stone by
Stone also when it's a very risky
stone. ah so we shall discuss with them if they
Are more competitive. we will divert to
Them. Actually he has indicated
Disturbing Stones for
[music]
That. To Arun ji. I would like to ask you
How do you balance regulatory compliance with
The Need for
innovation in the
you see you know this particular
Industry S We Talk About the Regulation All
in
Insurance IRDA You Know IRDA Is
Regulating the Entire Industry and from
From January 1st onwards we've all seen
So many changes earlier from up to 5
lakh 5 crore premium you know we are we
getting a
Very you know good discounts in that after
that now 5 crore now the loading is you know is
To the extent that now premium is
Increased by at least a double you know
Premium has increased so just to have you
No, we have even talked to each other.
Ah chamber of commerce we have talk to
Government Finance Ministry No Regulation
Is there but as far as industry is concerned
I
I'm running the industry where I've made all
The Risk You Know Prevention Measures I Have
Taken and the Person Who Is Running In
The industry doesn't have any ah you
No feature and he is running like anything and
Both are treated the same way. then there should
B some regulation in that. there should be a
Difference. one person should get a good
Discount on that. other person should get
Loading on that. so everyone is if everyone
is treated that way so you know there should be
Sum difference. it to say there should be some
Discrimination, some type of operation of
Understanding on that. Yes, yes, that should be
There.
Thank you sir for that. Coming Back to the Same
Format to Mr. Ashish.
The question to you is what you are the most
Effective Ways for MSM to Integrate
Risk Management in the Business?
It's a good question. The risk to MSMEs
Management in its day to day business
If you want to involve the insurance company
You will also have to take a step forward. Right? Today
The insurance company writes down your risk.
₹00 Premium Fire of ₹1 Lakh or ₹1 Lakh
Of insurance. Very few people know that
If any claim comes then its almost 80-90
The insurance company would pay from its own pocket.
Is. He does not have any reinsurance.
So today from the insurance companies side also
There are a lot of proactive majors coming up.
Where they consider risk management as a
I do the necessity. Before writing a policy
I should know that I am in the godown
or who is covering the factory
I am doing that on the atom bomb, is it actually
There is a risk for me today's risk of premium
The insurance company does not have it and what Sir has said now
Point told that this is the problem of every customer
In India, my premium is increasing.
The number of individual customers increases
Corporate premiums are rising
So, consider yourself as an Indian community.
It is very important to understand why it is increasing.
It is increasing because of health care
Costs are increasing. Inflation of 15 taka
There is health care in India.
Where will the insurance company pay the money from?
Insurance Law of Large Numbers Pay Work
It happens. Everyone took a policy here, so some
People will make claims. Only one or two people thought of that
If you take a policy then it is a claim based policy.
The second natural calamity you are seeing.
Growing in India and globally.
Incidents are increasing. So
From the balance sheet of the insurance company
There is an impact. And thirdly, insurance is today
The company was never listed. He lists today
It has started happening. ICICI LBAD is listed.
There is Bajaj, there is God digit, there is New India,
There is GIC and many other companies will come soon.
Listed in the next 3 years. So when the stock
If the company is listed in the market then your
And I'm investing my money in it as a share.
Holder then corporate governance keeps increasing
which used to say that I know you
And I got you the policy today.
Shareholders question the board
Are. So to integrate Sir's
The question is one that I am saying again myself.
Will have to change the thinking. take a feedback
There will be 100 people here now.
Who has all the policies that ICICI
Lobard explained the fire machinery
Breakdown is the answer in front of you.
Man, the rest of the people only have awareness
No
Is. India's problem is the same
There is no awareness. Those who sell understand
I can't even do that. And what we want to understand
It is not covered at all. So this is vicious
There is a circle. So there is only one way to solve this
The way is to change your thinking as a consumer. Today
Through so many SME Chambers
Insurance company reaches out
We propose that we are unique for SMEs.
Want to bring the product. Unique Features
Want to give. Joe Risk Management
ICICI Lombard told they are one of the
Best in the country. Meaning I am a neutral
Person. There is no one better than the customer
Thinking about. There are also nationalized companies.
And it is private too. And those people who invest
You can see what they are doing. any other
The company will not tell you that we are
Will do everything. And trust me I am
Not Being Told to Endos ICIB. This is unbiased
I am giving feedback. So the insurance company
You can also get the policy from anywhere on this site.
SME Chambers through Lo, ICICI LB
Through your insurance company
First ask him what he is to you.
Investing in risk management?
Will he do inspection once a year?
What about your people and your factory?
The manager who issues the insurance check
He will explain what to do
Needed? Are you reading the policy? in that
What condition is coming in writing that you just
You give it a cost, friend, take it and go.
Make a policy, your work is done.
The price has been reduced, everything is not there right now.
You will not achieve anything by saving Rs 10,000.
10,000 plus any untoward risk
If it comes, you will be protected.
If I want to integrate my business
As an SME Insurance
In Perspective
So this peace to me and my ecosystem
It is very important to bring it. Sir, from an industry
Is MD. Sir is the MD of an industry.
Is she coming to the lobby together?
To do? Do you work in another industry?
What are you doing. You are from some other industry. So
If there is a collective lobby then there is a risk
spread would be
Is. Only then will the insurance company get any number.
Does not appear to meet the target
To spread risk. Then the insurance
The company will invest in you. Then that risk
Management will do it. Then you get what you want
I want price plus minus 10 20 30 taka
You will also get it because
Invest in insurance companies.
I Think This Is a Wonderful Insight About You
Know how important that insurance is
inside it but the only point is that more we
Understand it, are we ready to accept it?
Or not? That's the main thing which I think
You but up the question awareness part going
You too Rahul ji, I mean a question to you.
How Do You Ensure That Your Risk
Management Your Organization Support The
Long term residence and growth?
Our Risk Sorry Our Risk Management
The Framework Is Aligned With Our Long Term
Strategic Goal V Focus on Diversification
Both in our product portfolio and our
Market to Reduce Dependency on Any
Single segment like Hum Log 300 Plus
If you manufacture the product
We are not dependent on a single product.
live and serve different market segments
If we talk, auto is the automotive sector
There is agriculture. Then after that you
There are industries. We cater to all of these
Are. Along with that, we conduct a regular
Risk Assessment and Scenario Planning to
Stay prepared for uncertainty. where
Our factory comes with insurance, you know
Health insurance comes for workers
Health insurance comes. We all that too
things he keeps doing on a regular basis
Are. So that if something like this ever happens,
So we should be prepared for that. not that
We are prepared for the event after it happens.
Are. pre assessment pre assessment we
We do. Investment in employees
Training, Adopting Automation and
Maintaining Strong Relationships with Suppliers
and distribution
Distributors are integral to our
Resilience Strategy. This effort ensures
That We Not Only Stand With Challenges But
also turn them into opportunity for
Growth. This What We Do. Thank you. I have
A question for ICICI Lobar, what role does
Technology Plays in Developing Risk
Management Solutions Tailored For
SMS? A pin point questions on today's
Generation Kind of Things. So, the technology
Plays a very pivotal role in today's
World. No one thought of this 10 years ago.
that today our life can go on without mobile
No. Not even a second goes by today
The mobile which we forget. Ok? So
Without that this is not possible. So lots
Many in technological development this has
Been gone into it in the health segment, B
Into Fire Segment and Property Kind of
Segment. Lot of improvements about the
risk as this all gentlemen are saying that the
How the Risk Can Be Improved. So
Technology has played the very private
Roll. And going forward if you will see some
of my products Ankit has told that
AI has enabled so 1.65 lakhs claim of
Health Insurance Gets Settled With in 30
Seconds in my company. That's N Huge
Nobody can just think about that, that her
Someone should stand behind and give approval.
behind you inside him then when will you get your
1.5 lakh people will get approval for health.
Inside. So that is what we have
Created inu the system that is the AI
Enabled. AI enabled court system has
Bean Developed. AI Enabled Claim Settlement
The system has been enabled. AI systems for the
inspection of the plants that have also
Been Developed Right Now. so I have a
Classic example during the Covid times
First Day of Covid When India Got Shut
Down OK we had an huge claim at Vapi.
Ok. So How and That Was Not Possible for
Anybody to travel and to get the claim
settlement and that the claim amount was in a
Huge in the crores of the amount. so we as a
Technology What We Did Was That We
Developed a drone and by drone we did the
Survey and the claim was settled within 30 days.
Days of the in the Covid period. that is
House I think. So, that's how technology
Is Taking Shape in Insurance Right Now.
And within this industry I would say none of
The Companies I Should Not Name It. But all the
Companies are not putting their money in the
Technology. We as a Lumbard are putting
2% of our total gross premium in two
The Technology Development. So, that is a
Hughes Investment What We Are Doing
Right now. Thank you. Today
Investment Step In 5 years ago ICICI
Lobard had an event in Bombay.
There his earlier CMD Bhargavadas
Gupta ji has written this article on AI.
presentation was given to the OK industry and
I had said that this is a thought of our S.A.
group that we can process claims through AI
If you want to digitize medical then
99% of the industry is there, don't say what is this?
CMD is talking
And he said, I will give you as a company
I will show you. Exactly five years
what this gentleman is saying is
Absolutely bang on. ICICI Lombard has 5
Did Curious a year ago. Absolutely
Curious about what India is facing today
People have to sit in the hospital for 9 hours.
Approval is required after discharge
or to get approval for cashless
It also takes four to five hours. That ICCI
Lobard has solved and for
had to pay money
Are. Comes
Free Nothing Less
Free. GI Mean Now One More Question For
You for this evening that can you discuss a
Specific instance. There is one instance
Where Your Risk Management Approach Helps
Your Company to Overcome a Big Challenge. or came
think i told you also before that
During Covid time it was the claim of
Around 7 crore and it got passed after
ECGC with lot of paper work and all so
That could save us and then we were at a relief
But without insurance to work in our
Trade is very difficult today and as sir
Said very correctly, I will tell you honestly
My View Before 20 Years Back When We Talk
About the Insurance I Say Why Costs Increased
It is to increase. Insurance will cost,
The cost will increase. So we were taking this as a
Expenses. But today my thinking has changed and
It is an investment without insurance.
Like we were even careless for taking our own
Health insurance also. Hey, your health
What is going to happen to? Why take health
Of? Why pay premium? so as he said
That thinking has to change without insurance
Today. You can't step a one fit you know.
So it is the most important and that saved me if
That insurance was not there then may be
Was Not Here Today. So insurance is the s
He said food, clothing, shelter and insurance?
I agree with you. Thank you. Sir to you the
Question to you is can you also provide
An Example of How Your Company Has Used
Insurance to Mitigate.
Mitigate. Basically its a broking house. But
Apart from that I know myself being a
An engineer, we have a separate company.
Our company is Nexon Risk Management.
Nexon Risk Management deals with
Industry-wide systems check
By doing this we check the fire load. So generally
What is happening? in the insurance industry
People go and sit in the factory.
Got them insured. How much fire
In insurance
How much building to take, how much stock to take
How much is the value of your machinery?
The insurance is completed. Our
What if we have our own, one is mine and the other is mine
wing or we can talk our
The company's sister concern is Company. We are this
We want our client to
There should never be an accident here. What to do
Can you do that for him? For that, we have our
to sister concern companies that every one of our
You should do risk inspection in the client.
Convince them after risk inspection
do it. What is the biggest problem of MSMEs?
It is that brother, if the company is small then it has to pay every
Things to do keeping your funds in mind
Does matter. So we have created such systems for them.
We have designed it so that brother, you have people like us here.
SM is your SMC Corporation has fire
The NOC is very powerful in the middle that your
The industry should have a fire NOC.
Renewal of your license without NOC
Will not done. What did we do with all these things?
that all the standards of your corporation
Keeping in mind that our company is
His entire risk hazard is covered here
Considering how many people there are
How strong should the system be?
We will make whatever is required. They
Our company will install them from our place.
She does it. Its AMC is given. And
In almost 100 industries I have created
Systems are being installed. And you are surprising you
Wood Be Surprise. Not one in the last 5 years
The claim has not come inside that factory.
Not a single claim has been received. So what are we
Are you doing it? Along with insurance, we also
We try to ensure that our clients
Be educated. He should not suffer any losses.
Because if a big loss occurs then
The industry goes back many years. We
I have seen people getting ruined. Business
I have seen him working since. So this
Considering the scenario, we have designed the system
Made that brother we should do risk management
Also. In that we have more and more of our
What can we do for clients? We
People provide free of cost to their employees
Provide training. Day and Night, his team
who are engineering staff, their
The security team and their management
There are people from, we train them day and night
that in case of fire, in case of
What should be an accident? how do you
Should an evacuation plan be made? She's all
All the things are done in our company.
And it is a part of our insurance. So
We Apart From Insuring the People
Insuring the Industry Our First
The priority remains that in that industry
How do we manage its risk? that's a
Real Good Thought for the Industry Itself. So
With this Yash ji is coming back to you again
I am. with the question is that what
Future Trends in Risk Management in the
Future and Insurance Do You Believe Will
Benefit the MSMS the most?
For in the benefiting MSM for risk
Management Wise SI Mentioned
Earlier something as a fix add on from
Every insurance company wherever they are
Offering any MSME and SME policy that
Like that AMC of the year, there is no such thing.
It is very important for MSMEs to have a trend.
So that we can come and visit you once a year.
Will do a checkup. of your business plant
Which is a very small amount in premium
Can. and from an insurance company
Perspective, that is a lot of saving.
To save. So I See a Trend Coming Up
In the near future is insurance companies
Will Havely Invest in Risk Management
And Offer a Freebie That This Is by Default
We are giving to every MSME who is
Doing this. We come every three months to six months.
Will knock you over like an AMC
Whether the plant is correct or not is objective
Whether the plan is right or not is the butt back end.
The objective of the insurance company is that
How is the risk affected?
Preventive health will improve in advance
If we care, we will go to that doctor.
When you get a checkup done, the doctor makes a sound, right?
That you should control your food and reduce your sugar.
So if you are on the border then this trend is
It is very important to get into business because
Exposure for Insurance Company is Very
high and at the same point of time which sir
Told that Sir had an experience and an incident happened.
So if the claim comes, today there is a trust and the trust
Sir, I have not renewed any policy for 5 years today.
She must have done it, she would never have stopped it.
They will say that no matter what happens, that policy comes first.
Do it because I have received a claim so I
See a scenario where MSMEs will also
Gradual move towards risk management as well
I will bear the expenses myself. Ok? and invest
Will create awareness among our people
To do. Because the problem is of MSMEs
India has only one.
The cost which is a margin of 4 taka. you I
If I ask you for 25 rupees as expenses, you will have to pay it.
No one. Out of your business. you will speak
Whatever happens will be seen. Not in 20 years
If it happens, what will happen in the 21st year? They have a little
Knew Trump would do this in 21 years or so.
It has caught them on their back foot in entire
World Rather. So there is a contingency somewhere.
Planning SMS is also important.
From my side, brother, I am so ready for risk.
I will allocate. This is for insurance
I will allocate. at the same point of time
Insurance companies and lobbies also know this
It is important to extend a hand for the SMS that
We would like to give you the default policy.
Take it and along with it the law also overall itself is like this
Trends and Practices Bring Like Fire
Protection Systems or Hazop Analysis
Hazard Analysis is all about risk management.
There are some technical terms and facilities and
If the lobby also implements this then it will
Benefit the Industry as a Whole and Save a Lot
of Economic
Losses. He has made the point very well.
Actually, one more thing we are looking at
Which is our focus within the MSME sector
Is it our own intermediary or ours?
There are agents who often lack knowledge
Because of this, within our MSME sector
People are very much affected at the time of loss
There are. Because of their lack of knowledge
Because of taking improper policies, our
As an insurance company like
ICICI or others or our industry or
At high risk or within the MSME sector
The agents who work also need to be sharpened.
There is a great need to do it. Because if their
If knowledge is limited then whatever little knowledge there is
It is very dangerous. AGAR Knowledge Limited
If they have it then either they should not insure them or they
We can't speak for anyone.
But you should tell them how to do it.
You have to pay attention to the valuation. What
The risk has to be underwritten in a systematic manner. To you
Which industry should be included in which category?
Is. It is often seen that risk
The catherization itself was taken wrongly. what you
The policy taken is of that industry.
It is not taken at all. That is not a category. His
His poor claim gets stuck as he goes. So
Many things bring us together and
The intermediate ones should also move ahead.
There is a need to be educated. You also need them
There is a need to educate. Then go and
The thinking of MSMEs themselves also needs to change.
Insurance is just as important as it needs to be.
You would be in Shiv Shakti Market
Surprised More Than 70% of Traders Were Not
Having an insurance policy. and those in the 30%
There were more than 20% of them like Bhai Saheb
Told that the policy was due to bank loan.
He didn't even know. How big is this
There is a flaw within us. Night and day we
are looking. Even after that we
We take insurance so lightly. Bank
Must have taken the loan. CCOD must have been given to him
The policy has come for this. He was not having. Some?
The problem people are facing is that they have suffered a loss.
But the policy is running at the old address.
He changed his location about six months ago.
Did. This low awareness will not work today.
In date. MSME sector or small
Businessmen also have to concentrate too much on themselves.
There is a need to create awareness about all these things.
Is. I would like to make a point on this at SME
Insurance Promotion Council is our
What was the objective of forming the council?
What Sir told or the experience Sir had
Kia claims
Right
Advisory and Claims Assistance These are to
Core Things Which Attend SME Insurance
Promotion Council We Have Thought That We Want
To educate it, then after going home today
Next one week timeline you
Consider yourself individually as a business owner.
your accountant, your agent, your
The broker tells them to show me the policy.
What policy did you make of me?
Is? Ask your accountant what he or she did.
A policy has been issued on valuation. And
Say, yesterday a claim of Rs 5 crore, Rs 10 crore came.
How much will I get if I get a claim of Rs. This only
This is an activity, right? Any number of agents and brokers
You have taken the policy through K, right? First you yourself
do it. Trust me you will be shocked when he
It will say that this is not a cover or yours.
There will be no understanding, which is natural. All
Things are not known to the customer or his
No understanding
will be. You try this. And Then Next
Steps we suggest you do
Share the policies to the SME Chambers and the
Relevant Team We Will Advice You What Is
Good for you there is the gap and then we will
Take It From There On Step by Step
Very good discussion about it coming to Rahul
GI Mean Very Very Important Question
And Which Will Give Us a Lot of Inside About
It can you share a case where it is effective.
Discuss Management
Actually supported the you know ah navigate
Very significant disruption that your company
has ever happened in me certainly during the
COVID-19 Pandemic Our Operations Were Severely
Tested disruption in logistics and supply
Chen posed a major threat however due to
Our Earlier Risk Assessment We Already Had
Diversify our supplier base and maintain
Safety Stock to Critical Raw Materials
More Over Hours and Comprehensive Insurance
Coverage for Business Interruption Allow Us to
Manage financial losses during the
Temporary Production Hall. This Holistic
Approach Enable Us to Resume
Operationally End
Continuously Continue Serving Our Client
Without compromising on quality and
Timeline. This What We Did. Thank you sir.
One question for you I will have is a very
Variant Question and Got a Relevance in
Today's discussion is that can you share some
Examples of how ICICI Long Bird has
Helped MSMEs navigate and recover through
Significant
Transactions. So a first of all if you
Have I seen the ppts ah there is one
slide which was given under the press
Release. So first of all we have taken an
step nobody and an industry has taken
Steps to Give You in the Claim Settlement
Clause of 10 days. So for MSME it would
B and Immediate Basis Claim Settlement Will
B Happening Upon and the Second Part would B
that on those parts the majority of the
Claims which MSMEs fall into that is
On the Fire segment and for what the STF means
The Perils Wood Trigger from The Perils I Wood
On the Fund. So, from our side, we have a
Commitment with an SME Chamber of India
And the association also. So, rest assured
From the lobbard side, all the claims will
Be Settled With in the 10 Days of the
Stipulated time. that is from our
Side that it will be commitment from icic
People are also sitting here as MSME businessmen.
Let me show you a small example.
How big a role does your software play?
is during claims. Today you do a job
Please do it. You can file your claim with your agent.
Talk to him about the stock.
What are the requirements in a claim?
The surveyor who generates the requirement
Write down all the requirements. Then
You can add your accountant to your software.
Tell me, all these sheets or as many as you can
They require stock statement
Is everything coming out of my software or not?
It is coming out. A very small example of this
Let me tell you. If you are a normal software
are using and at that time the claim
Surveyor generates your requirement on time
If he does, then people will have to suffer for four to six months.
It takes time to fulfill the requirement
Is. what we have started doing that at the
Time of Taking Policy We are
Explains the requirements and speaks to them
That you should tell your accountant about all this.
Get all the reports and give them to us. No
If so, talk to your vendor about our
All this is inside the software
Include facilities. Including New
Modules inside to gate. Yes, that you know
What happens if there are four or six people working there?
It takes months that you very same day surveyor
They take it out and give the sheet. all your
Things that save you so much time. These
It's the little things that you pay attention to
Is required. Thank you. thank you very much
For this wonderful discussion sir. I Mean We
Have been discussing a lot. And I think we
I've got some points for you too.
Talking About Prevention Is Better Than Cure
Then educating our team so that you know they
Can Actually Provide the Best and the
correct solutions out in the market which will
Actually you know create a much better health
Out in the MSM segments right right right
right thank you so much